Having felt an earnest call to ministry since college, I have been preparing for both foreign missions and domestic church ministry through internship opportunities, academic study, voracious reading, intense dialog, and a foray into electronic publishing. While my primary focus has been church health, including church planting and church strengthening, I have been gifted in personal counseling and have experience in adoption ministry. I hope to transition into ministry prior to or upon graduation.

I affirm the Abstract of Principles, the Baptist Faith and Message 2000, the Chicago Statement on Biblical Inerrancy, and the Danvers Statement on Biblical Manhood and Womanhood.

Personal Background

Spouse

Kathryn Rose, married December 22, 2007

Children

Vernon Ray, IV (10), Brooklyn Leigh (7), Emma Grace (3), Seth Christopher (infant)

Our three eldest came into the family in 2011.

Contact

81 McDowell Dr.

Wake Forest, North Carolina 27587

vernon.king@outlook.com | (817) 458-8174

Website: http://www.vernonking.org

Family blog: http://www.adoptedbytheking.com



Education

Southeastern Baptist Theological Seminary | Wake Forest, North Carolina

Currently pursuing *Master of Divinity in Christian Ministry*

Anticipated graduation: December 2014

GPA: 4.0

Southwestern Baptist Theological Seminary | Fort Worth, Texas

Coursework toward Master of Divinity in Missions

2009 - 2011

GPA: 4.0+

Texas A&M University | College Station, Texas

Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering

GPA: 4.0, summa cum laude

May 2007

Relevant Experience

New Song Church | Windhoek, Namibia

Missionary Intern

May 2007 - August 2007

Residential intern with an IMB missionary church and youth ministry:

- Assisted in the leadership and administration of a 150+ youth outreach program
- Helped host two American youth mission teams for two weeks each
- Provided technical support for church, youth ministries, and camp

Pillar on the Rock | Ecclesiological Online Magazine

Co-founder and Editor, www.pillarontherock.com

2009 - 2011

Wrote and edited articles promoting healthy local churches:

- Article reprinted in B&H book, Preach: Theology Meets Practice, by Dever and Gilbert
- Edited 100+ articles; Authored 50+ articles (www.pillarontherock.com/search/label/PJ King)
- Wrote major series on divorce and remarriage, race, membership, and church discipline
- Grew the writing team to include six authors

Church Background

First Baptist Church | Durham, North Carolina

Member

2013 - Present

Although a new member, I am scheduled to serve in the following ways:

- Rotating Children's Sunday School and home group teacher
- Pastoral internship through Southeastern in Spring 2014

Church of Christ the King (SBC) | Fort Worth, Texas

Member 2010 – 2012

Considered faithful to the community and participated in ad hoc duties:

- Deacon candidate (moved out of town soon after nomination)
- Organized greeter and security rotations
- · Administered web technologies

Portland Avenue Baptist Church | Oklahoma City, Oklahoma

Member 2008 – 2009

Sacrificially served while discerning future ministry goals:

- Interim Sunday School teacher for College and Career class
- Break-out teacher for youth ministry
- Assumed temporary guardianship for twin teenage girls from the youth group

Trinity Baptist Church | Norman, Oklahoma

Attended 2007 – 2008

Actively participated before planned move out of town.

First Baptist Church | Bryan, Texas

Member 2003 – 2007

Engaged in ministry during full tenure of college:

- Served as a youth leader
- Participated in college discipleship programs

First Baptist Church | Woodway, Texas

Member 1992 – 2003

Raised by my parents to be a faithful member:

- Baptized by Michael Toby, 1992
- Served on student leadership team during high school
- Counseled as a college leader for youth camps and mission trips

Professional History

Southeastern Baptist Theological Seminary | Wake Forest, North Carolina

Software Developer May 2013 – Present

FTS International | Fort Worth, Texas

Lead Software Developer May 2011 – January 2013

Led a team of five engineers and served as a point of contact with management

Deloitte Consulting | Dallas, Texas

Software Consultant, Homeland Security January 2011 – May 2011

FIS | Oklahoma City, Oklahoma

Senior Programmer Analyst October 2009 – November 2010
Programmer Analyst II September 2007 – October 2009

Hewlett-Packard | College Station, Texas

ASIC Intern May 2006 – May 2007

Texas A&M University | College Station, Texas

Peer Teacher, Department of Computer Science September 2004 – May 2006

References

Nathan Finn

Elder, First Baptist Church, Durham

Associate Professor, Historical Theology and Baptist Studies, Southeastern Baptist Theological Seminary
(919) 280-4309

nfinn@sebts.edu

Ryan Hutchinson

Elder, First Baptist Church, Durham

Executive Vice President for Operations, Southeastern Baptist Theological Seminary
(919) 761-2200

hutchinson@sebts.edu

Benjamin H. Arbour

Mentor and Friend (979) 574-1300 benarbour03@yahoo.com

David Jacks

Elder, Church of Christ the King (817) 395-2180
davidjacks1967@gmail.com

Jonathan Dent

Elder, Church of Christ the King (404) 667-7765 jdent_gt@yahoo.com